<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    <title>Suraj's personal website</title>
    <link rel="related" href="surajssingh.com" />
    <id>surajssingh.com</id>
    <author>
        <name>Suraj S. Singh</name>
        
    </author>
    <subtitle></subtitle>
    <generator>blades</generator>
    <updated>2023-11-13T03:55:57Z</updated>


    <entry>
        <title>Homepage</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/" />
        <id>surajssingh.com</id>
        <summary>Homepage of my website</summary>
        <content><h1>Welcome to my home page.</h1>
<p>Hello, my name is Suraj. You can use the above tabs to go to specific pages.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>About Me</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/about/index.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/about/index</id>
        <summary>Learn more about me</summary>
        <content><h1>About me</h1>
<h2>Who I am</h2>
<p>Hi, my name is Suraj (S.) Singh. I am currently a coding instructor at Coding Minds Academy.</p>
<h2>Preferred Pronouns</h2>
<p>I mostly prefer use of my name over pronouns when ever possible (avoids confusion), however my most preferred pronoun is: <em><strong>he/him/his</strong></em>.
<em>Example: <strong>He</strong> went to open <strong>his</strong> book, which was <strong>his</strong> as of last year and had been with <strong>him</strong> ever since.</em></p>
<p>Other acceptable pronouns is: <em><strong>they/them/their/theirs</strong></em>. 
<em>Example: <strong>They</strong> went to open <strong>their</strong> book, which was <strong>theirs</strong> as of last year and had been with <strong>them</strong> ever since.</em></p>
<h2>Interests</h2>
<p>I am interested in game development and education, and particularly the intersection between them. I am curiosity about many subjects, from mathematical and technology topics to art and history. I am also very interested in open source development.</p>
<h2>Current Projects</h2>
<p>Here are some projects I am currently working on:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://redeagle-p1.itch.io/skyjellies">Skyjellies</a>: A Unity programmer for this game.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/Tymire">Tymeit</a>: A time tracking web app that runs locally. </li>
</ul>
<p>You can find more project at: <a href="/projects">Projects</a></p>
<h2>What I am Learning</h2>
<p>Here is a list of somethings I am currently learning about:</p>
<ul>
<li>Svelte and SvelteKit</li>
<li>Rust</li>
<li>Godot</li>
</ul>
<h2>Contact</h2>
<p>I don’t have much of a social media presence, but I am somewhat available on LinkedIn and GitHub.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Portfolio</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects</id>
        <summary>A list of projects I have worked on.</summary>
        <content><h1>My Projects</h1>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Comp-Lang-Comp</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/comp-lang-comp.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/comp-lang-comp</id>
        <summary>A website to help compare the syntaxes of many different programming languages. Created initially out of my notes for the &lt;a href='https://exercism.org/challenges/12in23'&gt;12in23 Exercism challenge&lt;/a&gt;.</summary>
        <content><h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The idea is to have a website that can allow one to compare multiple different programming languages (or any kind of programming languages) easily. I primarily wanted to make this website to help catalog all the different ideas from a variety of programming languages to eventually make my own programming language.</p>
<h2>Current Tech Stack</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/slatedocs/slate">Slate</a>: Static Site Generator</li>
</ul>
<h2>Current Status</h2>
<p>Hiatus, learning more about other languages to add to the website, considering how to open it up for public contributions, as well as seeing if it can be updated from Slate. Likely to slow ramp up by the end of 2023.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Make A Lisp Implementation</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/my-mal.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/my-mal</id>
        <summary>A Rust implementation of &lt;a href='https://github.com/kanaka/mal'&gt;mal - Make a Lisp&lt;/a&gt; (a Clojure inspired lisp).</summary>
        <content><h2>Overview</h2>
<p>My implementation of Make a Lisp (MAL) done in Rust. Used to learn more about how to work with Rust, as well as learn more about certain programming concepts such as tail-call optimization. </p>
<h2>Tech Stack</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a>: Programming Language</li>
</ul>
<h2>What I accomplished</h2>
<p>Finished all the steps from the guide, now working on making some interesting improvements such as adding a <a href='https://alhassy.com/TypedLisp.html'>type-system</a> and adding a more <a href='https://readable.sourceforge.io/'>readable syntax.</a></p>
<h2>Current Status</h2>
<p>Hiatus, learning more about other Lisps to see what I can bring into the language.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Tech-Tree-Blog</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/tech-tree-blog.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/tech-tree-blog</id>
        <summary>A website to hold my blog post and notes on computer science, mathematics, and technology explainers.</summary>
        <content><h2>Overview</h2>
<p>A blog for teaching others online. I used this to help with my technical writing, as well as my teaching ability.</p>
<h2>Tech Stack</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</a>: Static Site Generator </li>
</ul>
<h2>Current Status</h2>
<p>Writing Hiatus, working on prime sieve code and trying to see if I can add interactive elements to the website to aid in teaching concepts.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Nomie 6 Stopwatch Plugin</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/nomie-stopwatch.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/nomie-stopwatch</id>
        <summary>A plugin I created for &lt;a href='https://github.com/open-nomie/nomie6-oss'&gt;Nomie 6&lt;/a&gt; to allow a more unified way ofusing the timer trackers.</summary>
        <content><h2>Overview</h2>
<p>I created this plugin to allow me to easily have timers (known as stopwatches for the plugin) which is tied to specific trackers. This would make it easier to associate timers with specific trackers.</p>
<h2>Stack</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/vuejs/petite-vue">(Petite) Vue</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org/">TypeScript</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/open-nomie/plugins">Nomie 6 Plugin</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Current Status</h2>
<p>Finished prototype, will be bringing idea learned to my new web app Tymeit.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Tymeit</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/tymeit.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/tymeit</id>
        <summary>A privacy respecting time tracker for yourself. Heavily inspired by &lt;a href='https://nomie.app/'&gt;Nomie&lt;/a&gt;.</summary>
        <content><h2>Overview</h2>
<p>A web app that lets you time track from anywhere and privately. This project takes ideas from Nomie and modifies it a bit to make it easier to track specifically with timing. This also let me work on a full project that uses <a href="https://svelte.dev/">Svelte</a> (through SvelteKit) and <a href="https://tailwindcss.com/">TailwindCSS</a> (through SkeletonUI). Develop following the YouTube tutorial <a href="https://youtu.be/P_A0qQ7AuK8">“Best UI Library for Svelte” by Huntabyte</a>.</p>
<h2>Tech Stack</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://kit.svelte.dev">SvelteKit</a>: JavaScript (Meta) Framework</li>
<li><a href="https://www.skeleton.dev">SkeletonUI</a>: Tailwind Framework</li>
</ul>
<h2>Current Status</h2>
<p>Basic Prototype finished, working on designing stopwatch system and better integrating data from Nomie.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Work Projects</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/work/" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/work</id>
        <summary>Projects I have worked on for work.</summary>
        <content><h2>Coding Minds Academy</h2>
<p>Projects I have either worked on or lead the development of at <a href="https://codingmindsacademy.com/">Coding Minds Academy</a>.</p>
<h3>Unity Curriculum Templates</h3>
<p>These are curriculum projects/exercises I had a hand in developing for a variety of levels for the Unity curriculum.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/Unity-2-Templates">Original Unity 2 Templates</a>:
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/Unity-2-Platforming-Game">Unity 2 - Old Platforming Template</a>: Template to help guide with developing a 2D Platformer. Used to help teach how to use Unity’s tilemap system, understand 2D physics, and save data across levels.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/Unity_2_RTS_Game">Unity 2 - RTS Template</a>: A simple RTS template to provide scaffolding for learning about inheritance and polymorphism.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/Unity-2-Tower-Defense-Templat">Unity 2 - Tower Defense Template</a>: A simple tower defense game used to help teach Unity’s scriptable object. Modified from the Unity 2 RTS project to reduce the number of things students need to learn about the template and replaces it in the curriculum.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/Unity-2-Platforming-Template">Unity 2 - New Platforming Template</a>: An updated 2D platform for Unity 2, focusing on improving assets and clearer lesson flow.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/Unity-2-Module-3---Unity-Exercises">Unity 2 - Module 3 Exercises</a>: 5 exercise scenes to help reinforce Unity concepts learned. Each exercise is a mini-game, including a UI-only guess the number game, 3D cannonball simulator, and 3D platformer.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/Obstacle-Course-Project">Unity 3 - Module 1 Obstacle Course</a>: A simple 3D obstacle course that is used to teach Unity’ new Input System and local computer multiplayer.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/MultiplayerPongTemplate">Unity 3 - Multiplayer Pong Template</a>: A simple Pong setup framework to help teach multiplayer using Unity’s Netcode for GameObjects.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/Steam_NGO_Example">Unity 3 - Steam NGO Example</a>: A set of scenes showing how to combine Steam and Unity’s Netcode for GameObject.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/SurajSSingh/ML-Agents-Example">Unity 4 - ML-Agents Example</a>: A set of prefabs and scripts used to bootstrap working with <a href="https://unity.com/products/machine-learning-agent">Unity’s ML-Agents package</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Student Projects</h3>
<p>These are some student projects I helped with. For these project, I primarily assisted with programming and game design based on input from students. All of the game presented here were made in Unity using C#.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-07T03:22:59Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>School Projects</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/school/" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/school</id>
        <summary>Projects I have worked on for school. This include my undergraduate work at University of California: Irvine (UCI) and graduate work at  University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign (UIUC).</summary>
        <content></content>
        <updated>2023-11-07T03:22:43Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Withered Away by Team Alpha</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/school/withered-away.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/school/withered-away</id>
        <summary>A 2D platforming game for the Capstone class. Lead music, audio, and level designer for the game, and assisted with coding development.</summary>
        <content><h2>Course</h2>
<p>UCI – ICS 169AB: Capstone Game Project</p>
<h2>Technology Used</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://unity.com/">Unity</a>: Game Engine</li>
<li><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/csharp/">C#</a>: Programming Language</li>
<li><a href="https://www.apple.com/mac/garageband/">GarageBand</a>: Digital Audio Workstation</li>
<li><a href="https://fmod.com/">FMOD</a>: Music and Sound Effects authoring</li>
<li><a href="https://pernyblom.github.io/abundant-music/index.html">Abundant Music</a>: Music generator, used pieces as inspriation for my music</li>
</ul>
<h2>Role</h2>
<ul>
<li>Level Designer and Developer</li>
<li>Music and Sound Designer</li>
<li>Assistant Programmer</li>
<li>Devlog Writer Assistant </li>
</ul>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The capstone project for my Computer Game Science degree. Learned how to work from game prototype to final product publishing in a small group within a constrained time frame. Available for download on Itch.io for Windows and Mac.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Collabuilder</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/school/collabuilder.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/school/collabuilder</id>
        <summary>A reinforcement learning project using &lt;a href='https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/project-malmo/'&gt;Project Malmo&lt;/a&gt; to make an agent that can build a house.</summary>
        <content><h2>Course</h2>
<p>UCI – ICS 175: Project in AI</p>
<h2>Tech Stack</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.python.org/">Python</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/project-malmo/">Project Malmo</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>For this project, my team worked on creating a Minecraft Agent using Malmo which would learn how to build structures based on a provided blueprint.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Crowded Market</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/school/crowded-market.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/school/crowded-market</id>
        <summary>A Unity game designed to simulate a marketplace using a simple AI implemented using Navigation Mesh and priority queue.</summary>
        <content><h2>Course</h2>
<p>UCI – ICS 166: Game Design</p>
<h2>Tech Stack</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://unity.com/">Unity</a>: Game Engine</li>
<li><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/csharp/">C#</a>: Programming Language</li>
</ul>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Energy-Ball</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/school/energy-ball.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/school/energy-ball</id>
        <summary>My first Unity game, adapted from Roll-a-Ball template. Go through the level and build up energy for jumps. Available online on Itch.io.</summary>
        <content><h2>Course</h2>
<p>UCI – ICS 161: Game Engine Lab</p>
<h2>Tech Stack</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://unity.com/">Unity</a>: Game Engine</li>
<li><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/csharp/">C#</a>: Programming Language</li>
</ul>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>Teapot</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/school/teapot.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/school/teapot</id>
        <summary>The final project for Interactive Graphics class, focusing on using knowledge of the graphics pipeline and applying that to texturing a teapot.</summary>
        <content><h2>Course</h2>
<p>UIUC: CS 418 Interactive Computer Graphics</p>
<h2>Tech Stack</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/javascript">JavaScript</a>: Programming Language</li>
<li><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/WebGL_API">WebGL</a>: Graphic Library</li>
</ul>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>Final project for interactive graphics class, learned how to write direct mesh and vertex shaders in WebGL. Teapot has simple reflections with image and coloring for spout and handle.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

    <entry>
        <title>StrSol</title>
        <link rel="alternate" href="surajssingh.com/projects/school/strsol.html" />
        <id>surajssingh.com/projects/school/strsol</id>
        <summary>A (partial) implementation of String Solving with Regex in Haskell using transducers.</summary>
        <content><h2>Course</h2>
<p>UIUC – CS 421: Programming Languages &amp; Compilers</p>
<h2>Tech Stack</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.haskell.org/">Haskell</a>: Programming Language</li>
</ul>
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>An implementation of a string constraint solver in Haskell, focusing on regex and transducers. Based on the paper <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2111.04298">“Solving String Constraints With Regex-Dependent Functions Through Transducers With Priorities And Variables” by T. Chen, et al.</a>.</p>
</content>
        <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    

</feed>